Guide to the Manzanita Water Company Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Manzanita Water Company Records
1876-1916
SC0012
Manzanita Water Company.
1 Linear feet
Correspondence, journal, stock journal, bylaws, description of lands, water grants, legal documents and other papers pertaining to Leland Stanford's association with the Manzanita Water Company. Also includes papers relating to Leland Stanford's San Francisco properties and recommendations of the Pacific Improvement Company to sell Monterey Peninsula holdings.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Transferred from the Stanford University President's office, 1965
Information about Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Scope and Contents Note:
This collection contains correspondence, journal, stock journal, by-laws, description of lands, water grants, legal documents, and some papers pertaining to Leland Stanford's association with the Manzanita Water Company. Also included are miscellaneous records concerning the Vina Ranch and San Francisco properties of Leland Stanford and the Pacific Improvement Company recommendations to sell Monterey Peninsula holdings.
Access Terms
Pacific Improvement Company.; Spring Valley Water Company (San Francisco, Calif.).; Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893.; Vina Ranch (Calif.); San Francisco (Calif.); San Francisquito Creek (San Mateo Co., Calif.)
Collection Contents
- Miscellaneous letters (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Water grants (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Spring Valley Water Company (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Manzanita vs. Clark (Box 1, Folder 4)
- J. E. Foulds letters (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Assorted legal documents (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Land indices (i.e. West Union Creek, Corte Madera Creek, Bear Gulch) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Land indices (i.e. West Union Creek, Corte Madera Creek, Bear Gulch) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Maps (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Stanford University and water companies (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Description of land along creeks (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Manzanita Water Company journal, 1883-1886 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Manzanita Water Company by-laws, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Laws, ordinances and acts of incorporation affecting the franchise of the Spring Valley Water Works, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Manzanita Water Company stock journal, 1891-1908 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Contract between Spring Valley Water Works, Leland Stanford and Jane Lathrop Stanford, and Manzanita Water Company, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Report of G. F. Allardt and C. E. Grunsby, Inspection of San Francisquito Creek, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous papers pertaining to Stanford properties (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Pacific Improvement Company recommendation to sell holdings on the Monterey Peninsula, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Norton property. Vina Ranch. 1876 court decree (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Abstracts of title to San Francisco land: Western addition, block 270 and 271; Clay and Buchanan Streets (Western Addition block 269); Folsom Street beach and water lot number 434 (Box 2, Folder 7)